Hello everyone, I am Xueli. In this tutorial video, we will learn how to make a umbrella.
First, we need to make a frame for the umbrella.
To make the umbrella, we only need to make the upper part of the frame.
You can download the components used in this tutorial video in the comment section.
You just need to open the BOOM avatar project file and bring this virtual model.
After downloading this project file, we can create a template in the 2D window.
Here we don't want to create a particularly long template.
This template is almost twice its width.
Then press Ctrl D to create a symmetrical template.
Next, we select the heavy template.
Then use the icon in the upper right corner of the positioning ball.
This icon is the positioning.
After clicking on this positioning, click on the front of the umbrella.
Here we put the template.
In order to conveniently align the front and back of the template,
that is, the direction of our hair line,
please open the texture surface.
This way we can distinguish the front and back of the template.
The front is white.
The back is black.
The other template is the same.
Use the positioning tool to put it near the front of the umbrella.
In the process of adjustment, we can rotate the axis of the positioning ball.
Let them stick to the slope of the umbrella as much as possible.
The template I made is about 100mm long.
Then we use the line powder tool to sew the middle together and the two sides together.
After the simulation, the template will pass through the model directly and fall to the ground.
This is because the template is relatively small.
And the virtual model that we randomly imported in
has a surface diameter of 3.
Here we need to reduce it to 0.
In this way, we can ensure that the air outside the model is not thick and will not affect the collision.
After the simulation is started, the template will still pass through the three bones.
This is because the grid of the three bones is relatively large.
And the template we are using now has a random particle diameter of 20.
Here we open the model grid.
You can see that its grid is very thin and many.
But our software randomly created the template.
Its particle diameter is 20.
The grid is very small.
Because the particle diameter is the length of one edge of the grid.
Here we reduce the particle diameter to 5.
Reduce the collision thickness to 1.
You can see that this template will now hang on the three bones.
But now this template will slide down.
So we press Ctrl Z to return to the previous step of opening the model.
Pull the template a little narrower.
So we can see that this template will fit.
And it won't slide down.
The structure that covers the fish bone.
Its particle diameter is 5.
It looks like the grid is not smooth enough.
We reduce it to 3.
And then we start the simulation.
You can see that its grid is very smooth.
Because after the particle diameter is reduced.
The number of grid increases.
Its grid is also smoother.
Because now we have a lot of grid in the three bones.
So the template will not penetrate.
But here we take a look.
It is the same particle diameter.
It is also the template of particle diameter 3.
If it is placed on the side.
With a particularly small grid.
If we start the simulation.
This template will go through.
That is to say.
When you are using your own model.
If you find that the template is very unstable.
And there is no way to hang it on the model.
Then please add some details.
Especially on the side.
Now we switch back to the physical surface of the model.
Then because we have now completed a set of fish bones.
We will create a copy of the fish bone template.
And use the positioning ball to move it.
Put it on the three bones.
We will repeat this operation.
Put all the three bones on it first.
Such a relatively short three-bone template.
You can refer to the position where I put it.
Try to put this three-bone template a little forward.
Then everyone will say.
Can I make a relatively long three-bone template first.
Then directly put this finished three-bone template.
Copy and paste it to the side.
The answer is no.
Because if you directly create such a relatively long three-bone template.
Because it is now a three-bone.
It's a bit crooked.
If you just copy and paste it over a long strip.
Then we manually go to it.
The rhythm is more troublesome.
And in 3D space.
When we operate this template.
It's often because it's not accurate.
It may have penetrations with the three bones.
After penetrations.
We still need to manually adjust it.
It's better to create a shorter one first.
It's more convenient.
Just like in my video.
If you copy all the strips.
As long as there is no match.
It may penetrate.
Because the three bones are relatively thin.
The method we use.
Is to copy a relatively short piece first.
Then pull the bottom plate together.
Then start to simulate.
So you can slowly.
To simulate along the direction of the three bones.
Okay.
Now I have copied all the short ones.
These three-bone panels.
And put them in place.
You can refer to the position in my video.
Put them like me.
After putting it in place.
We can start to prepare together.
Slowly lengthen them.
Because the extension of the grid.
It will follow the original rhythm.
Then because our three-bone rhythm is relatively large.
So we try to stretch it little by little.
After selecting all the bottom plates.
Stretch.
Then you can take a look.
If I stretch a whole one directly.
First of all, its grid will transform seriously.
At the beginning.
This kind of rhythm is not obvious.
It may be okay.
But when it comes to the later rhythm.
If it's more obvious.
It may have some more obvious penetrations.
Or transformation.
You can see it here.
So we press ctrl z.
And go back to before.
Not so much adjustment.
Now we stretch it little by little.
When doing this step.
May need a little patience.
Because in order to make it more stable.
It's better to stretch it a little bit at a time.
Will be better.
So we will go back again.
After we stretch it all the way.
To the right length.
Here you can see.
I left a little bit.
Because I will do a flower border later.
And when you are doing the simulation.
Try to let the powder line.
The middle line in the middle.
You can see that its powder line.
Is in the middle.
If it is not in the middle, we can manually drag it while opening the model, so that it is in the middle.
In this way, it is more correct to sew the scattered surface on this basis.
After making a set, I may choose to freeze this set so that it is convenient for me to understand which versions I have adjusted.
Because the shapes of the frozen versions will not change, and their colors will be cold blue to indicate that they have been frozen.
When we have finished adjusting all the versions, press the number key 5 to return to the top view.
Here we will find that it has some asymmetries.
So we control A to select all the versions, and right-click to select these versions.
Next, we import an OBJ.
This OBJ can be found in the secondary key.
Its name is MorphTarget.
After clicking OK, we need to open its download type and select MorphTarget.
Because we have imported this OBJ file now, it is the same file as the previous scattered bone.
We just modified the location of some of its grid.
Because their number of faces and number of vertices are the same,
when we import it in the form of MorphTarget,
you will find that as the scattered bones change slowly,
these versions will also be simulated together.
This is also why we chose to untangle all the versions before,
because we need these versions to participate in the simulation.
Now you can see that it is a relatively symmetrical structure overall.
Next is the part where we make the scattered faces.
When making the scattered faces, we can use a tool first.
Here we click the tool under the measurement tool,
the tool called straight measurement clothing.
The tool is used to measure the distance between the points on the clothing,
or the distance of a whole circle.
Here we can first click a point,
then move the mouse to the point next to it,
and then click again.
In this way, the distance between these two points will be automatically measured in the middle.
After we have measured its length,
we can start to draw this triangle.
First of all, this edge, we can see in the attribute editor on the right side,
its length is almost 430 mm.
So we wait a moment, because we want to expand it,
we set its length to half of it,
which is about 215 mm.
Use the multilayer tool to click,
then move your mouse to the side,
along the horizontal direction,
we can refer to this smart guide line.
When its length is about 215 mm,
we start to draw,
then move the mouse,
then refer to this pink guide line,
make a triangle that is equal to the one we just drew.
Note that the highest point and the bottom,
the point we created at the beginning,
are vertical,
because this way we can expand it along the middle line
into a flat triangle.
Then we use the adjustment board tool
to put this board a little next to it,
select the middle line,
right-click, select expand.
Then it will expand into a complete triangle.
This triangle is the scattered surface
in one area.
Then we can use the measurement tool
to select the measurement line,
press the delete button to delete it.
Now we are going to start sewing,
but we can't use the line sewing tool here,
because the edge of the current triangle
must be longer than this scattered bone part.
We need to switch to the free sewing tool,
and according to this scattered bone version,
we need to sew the length of this scattered bone part.
Here we first find the line
that needs to be sewn in the 3D space,
then click in the 2D window,
move the mouse along this line,
and then click on the top of this line,
so that we have the length of the first section.
Then we have to find the bottom of this triangle,
start moving up from its bottom,
find the blue horizontal guide point,
so that we are equivalent to sewing on the triangular board,
and then we can start to create another line of sewing.
Then we can start to create another line of sewing.
Here we use the free sewing tool,
be sure to choose the length of the side of the scattered bone first,
so that we can click on the side of the triangle
and confirm the length of the sewing we want.
Because it won't sew to the bottom.
Here I am sewing,
because I am more skilled,
if you can't determine the length of the sewing,
you can continue as before,
in the 3D space,
the side you want to sew,
click on that side,
then go to the 2D window,
find the blue guide point,
when we sew,
you will see a long section in the middle,
then we need to adjust this section,
but I don't want the position of the sewing line that has been created,
to change,
so here we can use the sewing line,
we can use the sewing line as the basis to make a cut point,
use the edge sewing line tool,
here note that it is the edge sewing line tool,
its shortcut is B,
then select a set of sewing lines,
then right click,
select the increase point at the end of the sewing line,
then on the other side,
this one is the same,
increase the point at the end,
because we sew from the bottom up,
so the point on the top is actually the end point of the sewing line,
then we switch to the edge panel tool,
you will see that there are two more straight points here,
when we move the top of this point,
the part below these two points will not be affected,
so the sewing line between these points will not be affected again,
at this point,
we adjust it,
we can refer to the 3D window,
its sharp point should be located in the extension center of these three bones,
after we have created it,
select this panel,
move it to the side a little bit,
then press Ctrl C,
Ctrl V,
copy a panel,
and sew it on these three bones next to it,
because now there is a breakpoint,
we can use the line sewing tool directly,
we first sew the left and right sides of the panel together,
then the new triangle panel on the right side of the newly created panel,
we sew it to the three bones here,
if you are not sure which side it is,
you can click in the 3D window,
then find the closest edge to this blue point,
then to facilitate the better use of the sewing line,
we are here in the 3D window,
use the positioning tool to rotate,
then press the control key to simulate,
now the panels below the breakpoint,
we have sewed each other,
or sewed to the three bones,
then in the position of this breakpoint,
we put it together left and right,
so we have completed two three-sided panels,
then repeat these steps,
copy and paste a panel,
and then sew them together,
then after sewing,
let's take a look at the effect of the 3D window,
you will see that there will be some bone effects here,
this is because now we have a very obvious breakpoint here,
then we need to smooth this breakpoint,
so that its transition can be smooth,
then we click on a panel,
then find this panel,
then we click on this panel,
delete this straight line on both sides,
then we can start to simulate,
see the effect after it is deleted,
you can see that this panel becomes very flat,
then we will do the same for other panels,
Because we actually copy and paste each version, so even if we delete the straight lines on the version, their line length is also fixed, and there will be no problem with deformation.
After opening the simulation, you can see that the whole thing is more smooth.
But here we will see that there is a bit of a gap in the version, so we can first reduce its particle diameter to 15, and then reduce the impact thickness to 1, and then simulate it.
Because the grid of the sputum is relatively thin and small, the particle diameter of the version is relatively large, so we may have some penetrating problems in the simulation under the particle diameter just now.
This is okay, we can gradually reduce it through the subsequent particle diameter to repair it.
If you have any questions, please feel free to contact me.
If there is still an unstable place, we can reduce the particle diameter to 10 and start the simulation.
After reducing the particle diameter, we will find that there is still some instability here.
Generally speaking, when we encounter such penetrating problems, we may choose to simulate the version a little further away, or use the option to select the mobile grid tool to move them.
But here you will find that it is still a little unstable.
At this time, we have to find the inside through this version.
Let's go back to the frozen version to check if it is a problem with the frozen version.
Now we select the external version and press Shift-Q to hide it.
After hiding this version, find the version inside and select this version to activate.
Let them simulate each other, and then freeze the internal version.
When activating the simulation, we must remember which side of the triangular version you are activating.
In this case, we activate the corresponding triangular version on this side.
In fact, if you encounter such a problem, it is because the particle diameter of the internal and external layers is relatively different, and the internal version has been frozen for a long time.
Some friends may ask why I only activate one side of the version and not activate all the triangular versions.
That's because the material on the external layer is made by these powder lines.
This is because the material on the external layer is very smooth and smooth.
When we only activate one side of the triangular version, the other side will have a limitation.
Because the other side of the version is frozen.
Through the three-dimensional window, we will see that most of them are in a tight state and are under a lot of pressure.
If we activate the two triangular versions at this time,
the powder lines between the external layer and the external layer will continue to move.
The powder lines will continue to stretch the triangular version.
At the same time as the triangular version is transformed, the powder line will also transform.
So we will freeze one side of it to ensure that the position of the middle powder line is fixed.
Ensuring that the position of the middle powder line is fixed also ensures that the powder surface can continue to maintain a very even state as it is now.
Next, let's look at the edge of the umbrella.
We can see that some of the edges of the umbrella are more obviously curved.
Some are more straight.
Through the force image, we can see that the force it receives on different sides is different.
Because the distance between each umbrella bone is different.
If you are a completely even umbrella bone, their strength should be the same.
But now the distance between the umbrella bone and the umbrella bone is different.
So there is a small space between some sheets.
But the sheet of the umbrella is relatively large.
It will bend if there is an excess amount.
And these straight places are usually the distance between the umbrella bone and the umbrella bone.
So the umbrella is tight.
In such a case, first you can choose to make this sheet a little bigger.
We just need to stretch the points at the bottom of the two sides a little bit.
Here we can see that it is obviously curved.
Because of its current sheet.
The sheet becomes larger and wider.
On the other hand, if you want the edge of this sheet to become straighter.
You should make this sheet a little narrower.
For example, this sheet next to us.
After we find this sheet, we point it twice.
Press the Shift key to flatten it a little bit.
So we narrowed this sheet.
After opening the model, you can see that its bottom is a little bit straighter.
In addition to the pattern, the fabric also has a more obvious impact on the shape of the umbrella.
Because of the overall structure of the umbrella.
The sheet will be more tight.
So our default fabric looks like this.
But if we reduce the strength of its gold tail and the strength of the corner line.
Then the stretch of the sheet will become stronger.
That is to say, its stretching performance will be better.
It is not easy to be tight.
So we will see that its border will be more curved.
After opening the hardware picture.
We can see that compared to the previous hardware picture.
The overall strength of the umbrella now.
It's a little better than before.
That is to say, it's on the border here.
The pull will be smaller than before.
If you turn to the side view.
You will see that the middle of the umbrella will bend slightly inward.
This is because its stretching performance has become stronger.
On the other hand.
When the strength of the gold tail and the strength of the corner line have been improved.
Then the stretch performance of the sheet will become worse.
It will become difficult to stretch.
Because it is not easy to stretch.
So the sheet will be very tight at the edges.
This is why we now look at it.
On the other hand, I feel that it is very flat at the bottom.
There is no inner bend.
Now we can refer to this board.
We will see that there is a fold in this board.
That is usually because it is stretched in the oblique direction.
That's why there is such a pull.
We can reduce the strength of its corner line.
Because the strength of the corner line has become lower.
This means that the stretch performance of its oblique direction will become better.
It is easier to stretch in the oblique direction.
So that its fold will be flattened.
Next, let's take a look at how to deepen the traces of its current powder line.
When we open the high-quality rendering preview.
You will see that its powder line position is not particularly obvious.
Use the editor powder line tool.
Select the powder line between the umbrella and the umbrella.
In the attribute editor.
Increase the strength of its 3D powder line.
After modifying its strength.
We will see that its powder line effect will be more obvious.
Then we can increase its thickness at the bottom.
In this way, the hair line of the powder line will become wider.
It looks more obvious.
For example, I set the thickness to 1 now.
Although I can see it with my naked eyes.
Its effect is very exaggerated.
But if I open the high-quality rendering.
Because the lighting effect in different software is different.
The effect of high-quality rendering is closer.
In other 3D software.
In the latter part, I added some lighting effects.
You can manually adjust these values according to your own needs.
These 3D powder lines.
In fact, the adjustment is the hair line effect of the powder line.
So when you usually pour out.
Remember to remember to hook.
Pour out the hair line sticker.
To accurately pour out the effect of the powder line.
After the adjustment of the hair line of the powder line.
Remember that other powder lines also need to be operated in the same way.
Now because the umbrella is in a flat position.
The stretch is relatively large.
So it can't do the effect of bending the line inward.
In addition to the hair line.
We can choose the umbrella bone version.
Increase its impact thickness here.
Because the impact thickness is increased.
The air around it will become thicker.
So it will give this umbrella.
Along the position of the seam line.
To add some air.
To push it up.
It looks like the middle position.
It's like it's concave inward.
Because the middle of the umbrella sheet.
And the umbrella bone are together.
So the middle of the seam line is concave.
The two sides are because of the impact thickness.
They are raised.
So it looks like it's concave inward.
Because we used the impact thickness here.
So before you do this.
Please make sure that your sheet.
It's no longer in conflict with the umbrella sheet.
There is a conflict.
Compare the side.
There is no use of the impact thickness of the umbrella bone.
To form such a concave effect position.
The hair line here.
It looks more natural.
So in all of our positions.
After it has been adjusted.
You can also adjust it according to your own needs.
The impact thickness of these umbrella bone sheets.
You can choose to increase their impact thickness.
A little bit.
For example, increase to 10.
The position of the hair line.
It looks more obvious here.
In the process of simulation.
Remember to freeze these umbrella bone sheets.
Otherwise their conflict thickness.
It will also affect the distance between them and the umbrella bone.
The last part.
We can add some flowers to this umbrella.
When making flowers.
We can freeze all the umbrella sheet first.
Because I won't do it later.
Other operations and modifications.
Then we go to the 2D window.
Use rectangular sheets.
In the 2D window.
Draw a sheet slightly wider than the bottom.
This sheet is the flower side we are going to make later.
Then we use the edit sheet tool.
Press the Shift key.
Click on the top and bottom of the flower side sheet.
Right click.
Choose to draw a middle line along the inner line of the curve line.
Because we have opened this sheet before.
There is a break in the middle.
Here we use the line sewing tool.
There is no way to sew directly.
Then we can choose to use the free sewing tool.
Combine these two sections together.
Then go back to the 3D space.
We need to switch the sheet back to the texture surface.
So that we can distinguish the right and the wrong.
If the texture surface is thick.
The front and back of the sheet looks the same.
But if you switch to the texture surface.
The front of the sheet is light.
And the back of it will be black.
In the process of normal production.
Try to make the sheet face outwards.
Then we put this sheet in the 3D space.
Arrange it in its corresponding position.
Then press the control key.
Open the simulation.
After the simulation.
You will find that this sheet is too rough.
So we have to reduce the particle diameter to 5.
Reduce the conflict thickness to 1.
In this way.
Its grid will become more and more.
And it will be more difficult.
Interference with our three ancient sheets.
That's because of the sewing line of the sheet.
Plus its own gravity.
Will make the sheet fall down.
In this case.
We can give it some pressure.
Here you have to pay attention.
When we use pressure.
We have to set it in the opposite direction.
For example.
If we set it to a positive pressure.
Then it will be.
From the back of the fabric.
Towards the front.
A fixed force.
That is to say.
If you give it a positive pressure.
It will only get more and more pressure.
So here.
We need to set its pressure to negative.
We can see that it will gradually flatten.
Because the lower part of the fishnet is hollow.
So when you give it negative pressure.
It doesn't have a negative force.
So it may continue to sink in.
At this time.
First of all.
We can adjust the pressure.
To see if it can balance.
But if it still can't balance.
We need to go to the back.
Add a transparent sheet to it.
To give it a little support.
First of all, let's try it.
Reduce the pressure a little.
Or use the pressure.
Open the left arrow.
Enter a specific number of points.
To give it a little pressure.
But here.
We will see.
In the end.
It will gradually shrink inwards.
So we still.
Add a transparent sheet to it.
In order not to affect the subsequent simulation.
Here.
We reactivate the edge of the flower first.
Let it not participate in the simulation.
And it won't have a conflict with other panels.
Then we draw one.
With three-sided panels.
The same width of the panel.
Then use the powder tool.
Combine the two panels together.
Here.
We still choose the free powder tool.
Because there is a break in the middle.
Of course.
If you think it's more troublesome.
You can delete the break in the middle.
Move the panel to the ground above.
After opening the simulation.
It will simulate itself.
Near this panel.
Then we choose this panel.
When it comes to the fabric.
Apply a new fabric to it.
Here.
We can reduce its transparency.
Make it a transparent panel.
But it is still.
It is flexible.
It can prevent.
It can prevent the edge of the flower from penetrating.
Here.
We freeze this panel.
Then choose the edge of the flower.
Press Shift Q.
Show it.
Then choose to activate this panel.
And manually drag it out.
In this way.
There will be no problem after opening the simulation.
Now.
Because of the block of the transparent panel.
The edge of the flower.
Even if it uses negative pressure.
It won't penetrate.
Now.
With the block.
We can put pressure.
Apply it to it.
After applying pressure.
We can refer to the effect in the 3D window.
If the value of the pressure is too high.
It may look a little dark.
We can reduce it appropriately.
And we can apply a new fabric to the edge of the flower.
Use a default fabric.
Because we adjusted the rain umbrella fabric before.
The default fabric.
Its shape.
It may look a little softer.
Of course.
We can increase the bending strength a little bit.
Make its spine look more round.
More full.
And then.
You can choose to cover the panel.
Ctrl C.
Ctrl V.
Create a symmetrical panel.
And put it.
We need to sew the panel.
Near the position.
Then.
You can also use the line sewing tool.
Use the long side first.
Press the Shift key.
Gradually click.
Loosen the Shift key.
To complete the creation.
Select the right key.
Add to the side.
You can directly put the panel.
Add along the sewing line.
So.
Wait a minute.
Later.
When you operate.
It can all be used.
Add to the side.
This function.
To make it easier.
I recommend that you.
Directly put it in the middle.
Delete this symmetrical point.
After completing the covering panel.
After we finish it.
We can start to copy.
Adhere panel panel.
In the case of the panel.
It is best to do it one step at a time.
in one step.
Do not add a whole circle.
In this case.
In our arrangement.
Or.
After that, we can use the line masonry tool to masonry all the sides of the picture.
After the masonry process, if you find that there is a problem with the flower side and the flower side, you can manually drag the board to prevent them from intersecting each other.
Then we can import the umbrella cake and other umbrella structure.
Here, choose to import obj, first import bone2.
The loading type here, choose to add, do not choose to open.
Because the software is default, if you choose to open it, it will be replaced.
Then confirm the unit, etc.
Click ok.
bone2 is the internal umbrella structure.
Next, we continue to import obj, choose bone3.
Here is also the loading type, choose to add.
Then do not need to select the automatic production arrangement point, the umbrella cake will be imported.
Here, my umbrella cake and umbrella are made separately.
Then I can manually adjust the actual size of the umbrella surface that I created at the end.
Adjust the length and width of the umbrella cake.
After selecting the umbrella cake, drag its deformation axis, we can deform it.
This tutorial video is almost over here.
You can download the learning document in the top of the top link to learn.